The Boy Who Harnessed the Wind is a drama, history
film directed by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Against all the odds, a thirteen year old boy in Malawi invents an
unconventional way to save his family and village from famine.
William Kamkwamba, played by Maxwell Simba.
Trywell Kamkwamba, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Agnes Kamkwamba, played by Aïssa Maïga.
Annie Kamkwamba, played by Lily Banda.
Chief Wembe, played by Joseph Marcell.
Mike Kachigunda, played by Lemogang Tsipa.
The Boy Who Harnessed the Wind is a 2019 drama film written, directed by and
starring Chiwetel Ejiofor in his feature directorial debut.
The film is based on the memoir of the same name by
William Kamkwamba and Bryan Mealer.
It was screened in the Premieres section at the 2019 Sundance Film Festival and
began streaming in most territories on Netflix on 1 March 2019.
It was selected as the British entry for the Best International Feature
Film at the 92nd Academy Awards, but it was not nominated.
It received widely positive reviews with praise going
to Ejiofor's direction and the acting.
The film explores themes of africa, windmill, based on true
story, family power struggle, water for life.
The tone is emotional.